Guide to the Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne papers vvb
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
- Photographs
  - Photographs of Associates
    - Photograph of Colin Keith-Johnstone (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Alpeda, New York.
    - Photograph of Marjorie Hollis, 1921 (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Eugene Hutchinson, Chicago.
    - Photographs of Barbara Ling, 2 items (Drawer 7)
      Photographs by Stuart Black, Torquay.
    - Photograph of Phoebe Coyne, 1932 (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Dorothy Crawford, Santa Barbara, California, 1948 (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of an unidentified play (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Atelier Eckner, Weimar.
    - Photograph of an unidentified man (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Leonid Dalmatoff.
    - Photograph of Irmgard Von Rottenthal (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of a painting of Richard Berry Harris (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Signe Hasso, 6 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Miriam Marmein, 4 items (Drawer 7)
      Photographs by Soichi Sunami, New York. Notes on verso regarding Marmein's dances.
    - Photographs of Richard Odlin, 6 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Japanese Players, 17 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Japanese puppets, 10 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Kita No Company, Japan, 12 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Mei Lan-fang, 16 items (Drawer 7)
- Artwork
  - Costume and Stage Designs
    - Bloch, Bertram costume and stage designs for Cornish School production of The Princess Who Wouldn't Say Die, 27 items (Drawer 2)
      Various media, including watercolors and ink drawings.
    - Chicago Little Theatre program cover (Drawer 2)
      Ink drawing.
    - Cook, Crosby crayon portrait of Maurice Browne in The Unknown Warrior (Drawer 2)
    - Watercolor costume design for a dancer in Showboat, 1929 (Drawer 2)
    - Dow, W. ink and watercolor stage design, 1935 (Drawer 2)
    - Eaton, John and unidentified watercolor costume designs for Iphigenia in Aulis, 10 items (Drawer 2)
    - Flowman, Hilda watercolor costume design for an imp (Drawer 2)
    - Ginsbury, Norman ink and watercolor stage diagram for Viceroy Sarah, London, 1935 (Drawer 2)
    - Goffin, Peter and Natalia Petrovna pencil and watercolor costume design for Turgenev's A Month in the Country, London, 1936 (Drawer 2)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond pencil sketches, New York, 1921; 4 items (Drawer 2)
    - Jonson, Raymond ink design for wood block print for Medea, ca. 1920 (Drawer 2)
    - Jonson, Raymond watercolor and chalk designs for King of the Jews, Chicago, 1913; 9 items (Drawer 2)
      8 watercolor paintings and 1 chalk drawing.
    - Jonson, Raymond photograph of costume design for The Pretty Sabine Women (Drawer 2)
    - Jonson, Raymond pencil sketches for Four One Act Plays, Chicago, ca. 1914-1915; 9 items (Drawer 2)
      8 sketches in a tabled. Envelope with sketches includes a list of items in an exhibit by Jonson at the Chicago Little Theatre.
    - Kreps, Ruth Margaret woodcuts, Seattle, 1925; 6 items (Drawer 2)
    - McCracken, Esther Helen (Armstrong) ink and watercolor stage and costume designs for Quiet Wedding, London, ca. 1938; 8 items (Drawer 2)
      7 ink and watercolor designs and 1 large piece of paper with a note by Maurice Browne.
    - Norris, Herbert ink and watercolor designs for Viceroy Sarah, London, 1935; 5 items (Drawer 2)
      4 ink and watercolor designs and 1 two-piece watercolor painting of a tapestry.
    - Odlin, Richard woodcuts from backstage at Journey's End, 2 items (Drawer 2)
    - Odlin, Richard watercolor costume designs, Seattle, 1921; 4 items (Drawer 2)
    - Odlin, Richard print of a Japanese actor (Drawer 2)
    - Ross, Harry Dick ink design for Mother of Gregory playbill, ca. 1924 (Drawer 2)
    - Sheringham, George watercolor sketch costume designs for Aude in The Unknown Warrior, 1930; 3 items (Drawer 2)
    - Mounted watercolor stage design for a Greek tragedy (Drawer 2)
    - Watercolor stage designs for Chicago Little Theatre production of Alice's Adventures in Wonderland, Chicago, ca. 1914; 6 items (Drawer 2)
      Accompanied by a note reading, "Designs for 'Alice in Wonderland', as presented by E. V. V. at the C. L. T., ca. 1914. Designer unknown; perhaps Carroll French of South Bend, Indiana; perhaps Kathleen Wheeler".
    - Stedman, Jeannette prints of Ellen Van Volkenburg in her roles in Anatol, Medea, and Trojan Women, 1914; 7 items (Drawer 2)
      Designed in the manner of Aubrey Beardsley.
    - Turner, John Hastings ink design for Punchinello, 1932? (Drawer 2)
    - Wheeler, Kathleen watercolor and chalk costume and stage designs for The Little Mermaid and Persephone, Chicago, 1915 (Drawer 2)
      The Little Mermaid: 3 watercolor paintings, 3 copies of watercolor designs done in chalk, 2 pencil and watercolor costume designs. Persephone: 2 watercolors.
    - Othello
      - Love, Montague Othello Christmas card (Drawer 3)
        Ink drawing featuring Paul Robeson as Othello and Maurice Browne as Iago.
      - Pryde, James pencil and watercolor stage designs for Othello, London, ca. 1930; 14 items (Drawer 3)
        5 pencil and watercolor designs and 9 photostats of the same images.
      - Pryde, James photographs of stage sets for Othello and photographically reproduced drawing, 14 items (Drawer 3)
        6 photographs, 7 negative photostats, and 1 photographic reproduction of a drawing in the National Gallery, London.
      - Sheringham, George costume designs for Othello, London, ca. 1930; 22 folders
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for 2 senators and 1 gentleman in Othello, ca. 1930; 3 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for the Duke in Othello, ca. 1930; 2 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Roderigo in Othello, ca. 1930; 2 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Othello, ca. 1930; 6 Pages (Drawer 3)
          5 pages of designs of wigs, caps, bonnets, accoutrements, and other apparel, as well as 1 page of a costume design.
        - Sheringham, George costume design for Emilia in Othello, ca. 1930 (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume design for Lodovico in Othello, ca. 1930 (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Gratiano and Iago in Othello, ca. 1930; 2 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George pencil and watercolor drawings of Montano and Montano's gentleman in Othello, ca. 1930; 4 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Cassio in Othello, ca. 1930; 2 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for two of Brabantio's servants in Othello, ca. 1930; 5 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for two gentlemen of Cyprus in Othello, ca. 1930; 3 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume design for Othello's guard in Othello, ca. 1930 (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for blind beggar, musicians, and a clown in Othello, ca. 1930; 3 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for an admiral and sailor in Othello, ca. 1930; 2 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for a messenger and Cyprus servants in Othello, ca. 1930; 2 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for a herald, trumpeters, and officers in Othello, ca. 1930; 6 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume design for Desdemona's headdress in Othello, ca. 1930 (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Desdemona in Othello, ca. 1930; 7 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Desdemona in Othello, ca. 1930; 2 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George pencil drawings from Othello, ca. 1930; 5 items (Drawer 3)
          Drawings of Desdemona's attendant with Montano's gentleman on verso, a detail from the above, a gentleman's shoe, and a shoe for messengers and servants.
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Bianca, 3 ladies of Cyprus, and 3 female characters in Othello, ca. 1930; 7 items (Drawer 3)
        - Sheringham, George costume designs for Othello in Othello, ca. 1930; 4 items (Drawer 3)
  - Miscellaneous Artwork
    - Arnason, Barbara M. print (Drawer 7)
      Features a landscape.
    - Bax, Peter woodcuts: "The Stage Door" and "11 a.m. Full Company" (Drawer 7)
    - Bennett, Richard woodcuts, 11 items (Drawer 7)
    - Blum, Jerome S. oil portrait of Maurice Browne (Drawer 7)
    - Cage, Paul watercolor: "Man on a bucking horse" (Drawer 7)
    - Daniels, Belinda silhouettes of Maurice Browne and John Cowper Powys, 1915; 5 items (Drawer 7)
      4 photographs and 1 print.
    - Drewes, Werner portrait of Maurice Browne, San Francisco, ca. 1922 (Drawer 7)
    - Enters, Angna prints, 1930-1939; 9 items (Drawer 7)
    - Garnot, Lucy print: Cluny IV archway (Drawer 7)
    - Gray, (H. W.) and Co. broadside: My Man John (New York: De Vinne Press), 1915 (Drawer 7)
    - Guthrie, James Joshua prints, 29 items (Drawer 7)
    - Hallward, Reginald print: "A Vision of Death" (Drawer 7)
    - Handforth, Thomas drawing (Drawer 7)
    - Heaton, Clement pencil and watercolor sketch of an old woman (Drawer 7)
    - Jonson, Raymond photographs: "Summer" and "Grand Canyon", 1928; 2 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Jonson, Raymond portraits of John Cowper Powys, Miriam Kiper, Elaine Hyman, and Arthur Davison Ficke, 4 items (Drawer 7)
    - Jonson, Raymond print: Coon Alley, Dubuque, Iowa, 1914 (Drawer 7)
    - Jonson, Raymond photographic reproduction of design for Miriam Marmein in Evil (Drawer 7)
    - Jonson, Raymond print of South Twelfth Street, Chicago (Drawer 7)
    - Keen, Helen Boyd sketches, 4 items (Drawer 7)
      2 pencil sketches and 2 chalk drawings.
    - Koiranskii, Aleksandr watercolor (Drawer 7)
      Shows a girl in pink robes.
    - Lankes, Julius J. print: "An Original Woodcut" (Drawer 7)
    - Leighton, Clare Veronica Hope woodcut print: "Net Mender", Toulon, 1929 (Drawer 7)
    - Lundsted, Eva watercolor floral print (Drawer 7)
    - Mazzoni, M. woodcut print (Drawer 7)
      Shows a building.
    - McBey, James and Marguerite greeting cards, 4 items (Drawer 7)
      Photographic reproductions of original drawings.
    - Mongan, Dorothy drawing of Ellen Van Volkenburg, New York, 1967 (Drawer 7)
      Chalk drawing?
    - Mortlake, Harold wood engraving: "Agnus Die", London, 1931 (Drawer 7)
    - Muirden, Phyllis painting: California seascape, Portland, Oregon, ca. 1920 (Drawer 7)
    - Nordfeldt, Bror Julius Olsson portrait of Bernard Gallant (Drawer 7)
    - Nordfeldt, Bror Julius Olsson portrait of Maurice Browne, ca. 1912-1918 (Drawer 7)
    - North Chinese shadow play figures, 2 items (Drawer 7)
      2 heads made of colored paper pasted on larger sheets.
    - Odlin, Richard pencil sketch portrait of Louise Soelberg (Drawer 7)
    - Odlin, Richard woodcut prints, 16 items (Drawer 7)
    - P., F. engraving: "Autorità ed avvilimento" (Drawer 7)
    - Poetry Bookshop broadsides, 3 items (Drawer 7)
      "Love's Secret" rhyme sheet, London (no. 3); "The World" rhyme sheet, London, Curwen Press (second series, no. 5); "A Memory", London. Note by Maurice Browne: "The Poetry Book Shop was founded and run by my mother-in-law, Harold Munro, and his wife, Dorothy Browne."
    - Pryde, James Ferrier detail from Crucifixion, 3 items (Drawer 7)
      1 watercolor and 2 photostats of the original.
    - Ripszám, Henrik pencil portrait of Maurice Browne, 1930 (Drawer 7)
    - Ross, Harry-Dick greeting cards, 2 items (Drawer 7)
      Prints on foil paper.
    - Ross, Harry-Dick pencil sketch: "Margaret Ellen" (Drawer 7)
    - Ross, Harry-Dick print: "Tanganyika", California (Drawer 7)
    - Smith, Erik Johan etching: Ellen Van Volkenburg, Firenze, 1929; 3 items (Drawer 7)
      2 copies of an etching and 1 photoreproduction.
    - Smith, Erik Johan drawings: "Rockefeller" and untitled, 1923 and undated; 2 items (Drawer 7)
    - Smith, Johan Eric (Smith, J. S.) watercolor and pencil drawing: "Le salon célèbre de Mlle. Van Valkenburg" (Drawer 7)
    - Sterner, Albert portrait of Mary Aldis, 1908 (Drawer 7)
    - Stumpp, Emil ink drawing (Drawer 7)
    - Stumpp, Emil lithographic portraits of Maurice Browne, Berlin, 1930; 7 items (Drawer 7)
    - Teng-Kwei watercolor floral print (Drawer 7)
    - Thomas, James Havard drawing of Rupert Brooke (Drawer 7)
      Photographic reproduction on a postcard.
    - Woodcut on Christmas card from Loretto Clark, 1923 (Drawer 7)
    - Volkenburg, Ellen Van pencil sketch caricatures of Cornish Players, Seattle, 7 items (Drawer 7)
    - Volkenburg, Ellen Van ink portrait of Ruth Kreps, 1928 (Drawer 7)
    - Wise, Enid woodcut: "Pine Trees, Dartington Hall" (Drawer 7)
    - Prints and drawings, 14 items (Drawer 7)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook 1, 1883-1889 (Volume 1)
    Note by Maurice Browne: "This scrapbook concerns the activities of my parents, 1883-9."
  - Scrapbook 2, June 1889-July 1894 (Volume 2)
    Note by Maurice Browne: "This scrapbook concerns the activities of my parents, 1889-July 1894."
  - Scrapbook 3: Clippings, 1893-1904 (Volume 3)
    Note by Maurice Browne: "This scrapbook concerns the activities of my parents, 1893-5, including the circumstances attending the death of my father in 1894. It concludes the unhappy story told in the latter part of the 1889-94 scrapbook."
  - Scrapbook 4: Frances Anna Browne clippings and photographs, 1892 and earlier (Volume 4)
  - Scrapbook 5: Maurice Browne published poems, articles, letters, etc., 1901-1936 (Volume 5)
    Disbound. Note by Maurice Browne: "By: Maurice Browne, Magazine Articles Etc., Pamphlets and Leaflets, Gipping Lane, May 1936".
  - Scrapbook 6: Maurice Browne's activities in England and Chicago Little Theatre, 1905-1914 (Volume 6)
    Note by Maurice Browne: "This scrapbook contains several C. L. T. programmes and announcements, including some not found elsewhere. The early contents relate to M.B.'s activities before he went to the U.S.A. in 1910."
  - Scrapbook 7: Ellen Van Volkenburg Browne clippings, 1901-1904 (Volume 7)
    Clippings, programs, photographs, and ephemera related to Ellen Van Volkenburg Browne's college dramatic career.
  - Scrapbook 8: Ellen Van Volkenburg, 1906-1941 (Volume 8)
  - Scrapbook 9: Ellen Van Volkenburg, "Personal Publicity", Seattle, 1934 (Volume 9)
    Disbound.
  - Scrapbook 10: Chicago Little Theatre clippings and programs, April 1910-November 1913 (Volume 10)
  - Scrapbook 11: Ellen Van Volkenburg, "Relics of Chicago Little Theatre", 1914-1916 (Volume 11)
    Includes photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg as Medea and in other roles, as well as programs and clippings related to the Chicago Little Theatre.
  - Scrapbook 12: American Press Cuttings, Chicago Little Theatre tour of Trojan Women, 1915 (Volume 12)
  - Scrapbook 13: Puppets, 1913-1938 (Volume 13)
  - Scrapbook 14: Chicago Little Theatre clippings, programs, and notes, December 1913-May 1916 (Volume 14)
    Some items removed and housed separately.
  - Scrapbook 15: Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg, Chicago Little Theatre clippings and programs, 1914-1924 (Volume 15)
    Note by Maurice Browne: "This scrapbook seems to contain some programmes not found in programme-sets."
  - Scrapbook 16: Puppets, 1915-1920 (Volume 16)
    Clippings and programs with holograph notes by Ellen Van Volkenburg.
  - Scrapbook 17: Press-cuttings / Scrap Book III, June 1916-1917 (Volume 17)
  - Scrapbook 17a: Chicago Little Theatre announcements and programmes, ca. 1916-1917 (Volume 17a)
  - Scrapbook 18: A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1924; 2 Volumes (Volume 18)
    Photographs of puppets and puppeteers.
  - Scrapbook 19: Medea, New York, review clippings, March 1920 (Volume 19)
  - Scrapbook 20: American Press Cuttings, 1920-1933 (Volume 20)
  - Scrapbook 21: Theatre of the Golden Bough clippings, Carmel, California, 1924 (Volume 21)
  - Scrapbook 22: Maurice Browne, 1927-1928 (Volume 22)
  - Scrapbook 23: Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg clippings and programs, 1927-1932 (Volume 23)
  - Scrapbook 24: Cornish School, 1929-1937 and undated (Volume 24)
  - Scrapbook 25: Ellen Van Volkenburg, Seattle and Tacoma, 1926-1929 (Volume 25)
    Includes materials related to The Trojan Women, Devil's Sabbath, Cassili's Engagement, Paolo and Francesca, and The Princess Who Wouldn't Die.
  - Scrapbook 26: Ellen Van Volkenburg Cornish productions, 1933-1934 (Volume 26)
    Includes materials about Tobias and the Angel, The Wizard of Oz, Iphigenia in Aulis, The Wind and the Rain, and After Such Pleasures (Ellen Van Volkenburg reading).
  - Scrapbook 27: Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg, School of the Arts of the Theatre, San Francisco, 1922-1924 (Volume 27)
  - Scrapbook 28: The Drama: "Maurice Browne's 1921 Season in Seattle", March 1922 (Volume 28)
  - Scrapbook 29: Maurice Browne Theatre Association announcements and press clippings, Los Angeles, 1926 (Volume 29)
  - Scrapbook 30: American Scrapbook, September 1930-July 1931 (Volume 30)
  - Scrapbook 31: General Press, 1931-1932 (Volume 31)
  - Scrapbook 32: English Miscellaneous, November 1931-March 1932 (Volume 32)
  - Scrapbook 33: English Miscellaneous, January 1932-May 1932 (Volume 33)
  - Scrapbook 34: England Miscellaneous, 1932-1937 (Volume 34)
  - Scrapbook 35: Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg clippings, 1934-1956 (Volume 35)
  - Scrapbook 36: B. J. One, Globe Theatre, London, undated (Volume 36)
  - Scrapbook 36a: Photographs of B. J. One, Globe Theatre, London, undated (Volume 36a)
  - Scrapbook 37: Badger's Green and general press cuttings, Great Britain, 1930 (Volume 37)
  - Scrapbook 38: The Bowery Touch press notices, 1937-1939 (Volume 38)
  - Scrapbook 39: The Brass Paperweight, Apollo Theatre, London, October 1928 (Volume 39)
  - Scrapbook 40: Bridge of Sighs, 1939 (Volume 40)
  - Scrapbook 41: Bridge of Sighs, 1939 (Volume 41)
  - Scrapbook 42: Eastward in Eden, November 1947 (Volume 42)
  - Scrapbook 43: The Improper Duchess, Unknown Warrior, and Venetian, U.S.A., 1931 (Volume 43)
  - Scrapbook 44: The Improper Duchess, London, December 1930-March 1931 (Volume 44)
  - Scrapbook 45: The Improper Duchess, London, March 1931-January 1932 (Volume 45)
  - Scrapbook 46: Hamlet, International Season, London, England, 1930 (Volume 46)
  - Scrapbook 47: Journey's End English, January 2, 1929-January 27, 1929 (Volume 47)
  - Scrapbook 48: English Press Cuttings, Book No. I: Journey's End English, January 5, 1929-March 16, 1929 (Volume 48)
  - Scrapbook 49: English Press Cuttings, Book No. II: Journey's End English, March 14, 1929-May 31, 1929 (Volume 49)
  - Scrapbook 50: English Press Cuttings, Book No. III: Journey's End English, June 1, 1929-August 31, 1929 (Volume 50)
  - Scrapbook 51: English Press Cuttings, Book No. IV: Journey's End English, August 10, 1929-October 30, 1929 (Volume 51)
  - Scrapbook 52: English Press Cuttings, Book No. V: Journey's End English, October 21, 1929-November 23, 1929 (Volume 52)
  - Scrapbook 53: Journey's End English, December 1, 1929-January 23, 1930 (Volume 53)
  - Scrapbook 54: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 1: Journey's End American, March 10, 1929-May 14, 1929 (Volume 54)
  - Scrapbook 55: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 2: Journey's End American, July 14, 1929-September 18, 1929 (Volume 55)
  - Scrapbook 56: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 3: Journey's End American, August 31, 1929-October 22, 1949 (Volume 56)
  - Scrapbook 57: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 4: Journey's End American, October 10, 1929-November 14, 1929 (Volume 57)
  - Scrapbook 58: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 5: Journey's End American, November 14, 1929-December 8, 1929 (Volume 58)
  - Scrapbook 59: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 6: Journey's End American, December 8, 1929-January 1, 1930 (Volume 59)
  - Scrapbook 60: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 7: Journey's End American, January 1, 1930-January 23, 1930 (Volume 60)
  - Scrapbook 61: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 8: Journey's End American, January 23, 1930-March 2, 1930 (Volume 61)
  - Scrapbook 62: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 9: Journey's End American, March 3, 1930-April 13, 1930 (Volume 62)
  - Scrapbook 63: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 10: Journey's End American, April 14, 1930-May 14, 1930 (Volume 63)
  - Scrapbook 64: American Press Cuttings, Book No. 11: Journey's End American, May 15, 1930-September 14, 1930 (Volume 64)
  - Scrapbook 65: Journey's End clippings, Bermuda, Italy, Nairobi, Paris, 1929-1930 and undated (Volume 65)
  - Scrapbook 66: Journey's End biographical and anecdotal clippings, 1929-1942 (Volume 66)
  - Scrapbook 67: Journey's End English and Scotch, March 18, 1930-June 23, 1930 (Volume 67)
  - Scrapbook 68: Journey's End English and Australian, January 24, 1930-March 23, 1930 (Volume 68)
  - Scrapbook 69: "The Mother of Gregory by Maurice Browne", 1924 (Volume 69)
    Pohtographs, clippings, and programs. Made as a gift for Maurice Browne by Ellen Van Volkenburg.
  - Scrapbook 70: Muted Strings, People in Love, etc., 1936-1938 (Volume 70)
  - Scrapbook 71: Othello, February 1930-July 1930 (Volume 71)
  - Scrapbook 72: People in Love, 1937 (Volume 72)
  - Scrapbook 73: Shdanoff, George, The Possessed, N.Y. Chekhov Theatre Prods., 1939 (Volume 73)
  - Scrapbook 74: Press Book for La Prisonière, Journey's End revival, and Viceroy Sarah, London, 1934-1937 (Volume 74)
  - Scrapbook 75: Quiet Wedding, March 1939-August 1939 (Volume 75)
  - Scrapbook 76: Quiet Wedding, 1938-1939 (Volume 76)
  - Scrapbook 77: Three Blind Mice, 1939 (Volume 77)
  - Scrapbook 78: Three Blind Mice and White Secrets, 1938 (Volume 78)
  - Scrapbook 79: Street Scene, August 1930-November 1930 (Volume 79)
  - Scrapbook 80: The Unknown Warrior, Arts Theatre Club, London, 1928-1929 (Volume 80)
  - Scrapbook 81: The Unknown Warrior, 1928 (Volume 81)
  - Scrapbook 82: The Unknown Warrior, etc., Little Theatre, London, 1930-1931 (Volume 82)
  - Scrapbook 83: The Venetian, and The New Gossoon, Little Theatre and Apollo Theatre, 1931 (Volume 83)
  - Scrapbook 84: The Unknown Warrior, U.S. Tour, 1931 (Volume 84)
  - Scrapbook 85: We Are the People American clippings, December 1928-January 1929 (Volume 85)
  - Scrapbook 86: Wings over Europe American clippings, December 1928-January 1929 (Volume 86)
  - Scrapbook 87: Wings over Europe American clippings, 1928-1928 (Volume 87)
  - Scrapbook 88: Reviews of Too Late to Lament, 1955 (Volume 88)
    Note: "This scrapbook was especially made for them by McNally of Dartington Hall, Ltd."
  - Scrapbook 89: Album containing early poems by Maurice Browne, Arthur Ficke, H. E. Monro, and others, from "early undergraduate days", ca. 1901-1906 (Volume 89)
- Printed Material
  - Clippings
    - Maurice Browne clippings
      - Notices of Maurice Browne's early books, 1905 (Box 39)
      - Maurice Browne and Journey's End clipping and ephemera, 1931 and undated; 2 items (Box 39)
    - Ellen Van Volkenburg clippings
      - Ellen Van Volkenburg notices and programs, undated (Box 39)
      - Ellen Van Volkenburg clippings and memorabilia, 1909-1912 and undated (Box 39)
      - Ellen Van Volkenburg clippings, 1968-1969 and undated (Box 39)
      - "The Most Remarkable Girl in Chicago: Ellen Van Volkenburg of the Marvelous Memory by Mme. Qui Vive.", October 29, 1909 (Oversize 1)
        1 newspaper leaf and 1 positive photostat. Published in the Sunday Record-Herald, Chicago, Ill.
    - Dorothy and Leonard Elmhirst clippings: Dartington Hall clippings, 1974 and undated (Box 39)
    - Clippings, 1921-1936 and undated (Box 39)
  - Organizations and places
    - Chekhov Theatre Studio, Dartington Hall, and Ridgefield, Connecticut brochures, playbills, and other items (Box 39)
      Many items acquired from sources other than Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg.